foreign
[Music]
Ty's automation tutorial
so try sentence has released its new
product called tricentious device Cloud
on 8th of August
so this session I'm going to explain you
what are all the
different features that are available in
trisil disk device cloud and then I'm
gonna give you a hands-on experience how
does this try sentence device Cloud
works
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I post more
videos
so what is try sentence device group so
basically try sentence device Cloud a
device is a device form that enables
teams to test on physical smartphones
and tablets in the cloud so it supports
the most popular versions of Android iOS
devices including Apple iPhone Samsung
Galaxy and Google pixel Oppo Find or
Vivo and more okay so how it works
so before we have a hands-on experience
let me explain the key features of this
tricentious device cloud
so this tri-centers device Cloud can
also integrated with the automation
tools like try sentence Tasker and then
try sentence testing automation tools so
you can run your automation scripts on
present this device cloud
by using different mobile devices and
then you can compare all the test
results of your automation scripts in
different mobiles right and also apart
from doing per functional testing and it
also has a capability of
doing a performance results also you can
verify the performance results also okay
how so let me first explain the key
features so first key feature is remote
control
so this remote control gives you an
overview of the devices which are
connected to your
transientist device Cloud space
and try centers device cloud has lot of
devices
configurations ranging across different
brands different device models operating
systems platform configurations as well
as different locations
so you can establish a remote mirroring
session to your device
and you can interact with the device
with mon mirroring session you can use
the tools section to work on ADB
Commands basically you can send your ADB
Commands to your respective device right
you can manage apps you can upload the
required applications onto a device
which is configured in the cloud
okay and also you can perform
exploratory testing where you can take
the screenshots for your exploratory
scenarios and also you can record your
exploratory scenario
so basically you can do screen recording
of your exploratory scenario so that is
one key feature of your price entrance
device group and second key feature
performance sessions
so every every single test name and
Tasker test performed on tricente's
device cloud is gonna result in a
performance session
okay so the C is an extension of your
functional testing feedback that you are
providing with Testament task
so tricent is extending it with user
experience and performance data
so here you can get
the overview of screen recording of your
mobile device screen also you can get
time series of all the recorded metrics
that try sentence collects during your
execution of automation tests on the
mobile
so metrics related to what you can have
basically UI blurriness Matrix
blockiness of the your mobile and what
is your contrast and brightness of your
screen right and also uh communicative
networks packets monitoring and
collecting info about your CPU load
memory load and Battery consumption
right all these metrics you can collect
so all of these collected metrics are
Telemetry data
processes by a mobile engine mobile AI
engine mobile artificial intelligence
engine so try sentence device cloud
has its own mobile artificial
intelligence engine
which collects all these metrics and
that results into a
creating I mean creative issue cards so
basically whatever the metrics I told
you right Network related metrics uh
mobile UI related metrics right all
these metrics will be collected by
mobile a engine and IT issues the issue
cards which gives you the overview of
your user experience and performance
issues like what like low frame rates
that is one issue card it can issue a
poor video quality a long loading
animations or slow downloads so these
are all the issue cards it's going to
issue by using mobile a engine by
collecting enormous metrics I discussed
with you
right and the other key feature is
performance monitoring
so whatever the performance sessions I
told you in my previous uh feature right
the second feature so that performance
sessions can be grouped to user flows
once you did that you can monitor
collected metrics user experience and
performance kpis over the time so you
can understand how user experience and
performance kpis are evolving over the
time while you are making changes or
while you are making enhancements to the
applications right so let's say you
reported some issue cards to deliver so
developer what developer will do
developer will has the application once
he enhanced the application again he
deploys it to your mobile device right
cloud and then
you again execute them now over the time
you can monitor the performance how the
performance is evolving right by using
performance monitoring section okay so
you can also compare two different
sessions against each other
so these are all the different
advantages so now let me show you all
these features
by accessing my own try sentence device
cloud and I'm Gonna Give You hands-on
experience okay let's jump onto the
system
so let us have a Hands-On overview of
the try sentence device Cloud okay so if
you see this is my try sentence device
Cloud session okay where I have some
devices okay so first of all
there are three
features
key features right that are available in
try centers device Cloud as I explained
you okay the first one so first one is a
remote control section
so let's see what is remote control
section okay if you see on the screen
this is your remote control section
where you have a lot of devices okay
which are connected to your transientist
device Cloud okay TDC has lot of devices
configuration ranging across
different brands if you see different
brands Samsung right and then you always
also have Apple devices Google devices
and then you have Oppo devices all these
devices you can find in the try sentence
device Cloud so let me go to my device
Cloud okay where you can see I have two
devices on the screen one is
Samsung and the other one is Apple so
these two devices are configured to my
tricentious device Cloud okay because
it's a trial version I have only two
devices in my session but in real time
you will have you will have enormous
list of device clouds that you can
access
in try sentence device
Cloud okay so and also
you can establish a remote mirror
session to your device let's assume so
this is my Samsung okay I want to
establish a remote mirror session how
you just click on start as soon as you
click on start it's going to establish a
Remote device
session where you can interact with the
device with mirroring session okay you
can use the tools see this is my mobile
right you can interact with this mobile
I can click on Chrome
it opens the Chrome right I can see here
and then again go back to your menu and
then you can scroll to the top
scroll to the right right you can see
and also you can see here on right side
this device is actually this device
location you can basically simulate the
device location also so this the
particular device is from this location
okay if you scroll down you can see over
overview of your the device real device
on cloud this is your serial number what
is the carrier right what is the network
and then if you scroll down uh this is
your Samsung what is the model right and
then what is the OS it's a version 13
which is latest version correct
and also uh it shows you the battery
percentage and everything CPU what is
the memory in all these details you can
see for a particular given device okay
and also you can interact with this
apart from interacting with the device
you can use the tools section if you see
on the right side right this is your
tools section okay under Tools section
you can basically
use ADB Commands also if you see here
see you can send the ADB Commands scroll
down see ADB shell you can run your ADB
Commands also right you can manage apps
also as I told you right let's go back
to once the tools is here if you go to
the next section called apps where you
can upload your APK files simply what
you need to do is choose an APK file and
select APK file from your
system
right as soon as you select and then
open it will install the APK file means
you can install the apps on your Samsung
device okay that is one advantage okay
and also you can do exploratory testing
by using start regarding session
okay let's you see here let me start
recording record with network okay
now it started recording your session
now whatever
actions that you perform on this mobile
device see it is now recording right
and whatever I perform the
action here
demo
Dot webshop
webshop
Dot
tricentice.com
let's say
I'm what I'm doing actually I'm just
opening one website
enter so now it will land on to your
sample website of your present is
correct so now again you can stop the
recording
so basically as soon as you stop the
recording it establishes the entire
session I'm gonna show you later that
one okay so that is one thing and the
next one is
you can also take the screenshots right
so you can take screenshots you can
record the sessions right and then
screenshot is here okay you can
basically take the screenshot
and see take the screenshot see it took
the screenshot of your mobile State let
me just again go back here now again
take a screenshot see screenshot of
particular snapshot so if you find a bug
let's say you logged in here you found
found a book okay you entered your
username and then you hit login you are
expecting some error message let's say
this is not as expected you can simply
take a screenshot that's it so you can
take a screenshot so that's the
advantage so that is one thing so this
is all about your remote control section
if you see this is your remote control
section correct so there is a next one
is your performance session section
so let's go back to your performance
section this is your performance
sessions go to Performance
so before I go to Performance
I want to see here I want to stop my
session right let's go here I want to
stop the session
simply stop using it
so now stopped now let's go back to
Performance session
if you see in the performance session
every single testing so let's say I have
executed the I have performed the manual
testing here right but whereas if you
execute any test case from try sentence
task or if you execute any test case
from testif that means you are executing
automation test cases
on this Cloud device then what happens
it establishes
a performance basically it is gonna
perform on try sentence device cloud and
it's gonna result in a performance
session let's assume because
instead of Performing automation what we
did we performed manual testing right
this is what we did now if you see a
session has been established here where
in the performance session
aha interacted with the same device
for three minutes I mean before three
minutes ago and it formed a data
analysis okay let's go to
Whenever there is an action performed on
the device
from Tosca are from testing or manually
is performance session will be
established okay so now this is an
extension of your functional testing
feedback that you are performing with
testimer task so try sentence is
extending it with user experience and
performance data okay where you just
click on this to access the performance
data
you can click on your waterfall UI
so here you can get a overview
of the screen recording of your Mobile's
device okay you can get the time series
where let me scroll down here see
you can see all the overview of the
metrics okay session wide Matrix domain
metrics
host metrics and burst metrics let me
scroll down here so if you see here
you can get time series basically time
series of all the recorded metrics the
tricent is collects during execution of
mobile test
okay what kind of metrics you will have
you will have a matrix like let's say
what is Page
content if you see right side you can
see the screen also okay and what is
your frame rate and what is your screen
change and uh also what is the
concurrency
and then what is your download speed
what is your HTTP throughput right and
also what is your network in bytes right
and so on and if you see apart from
these Networks uh let's scroll down
uh Network related you have a CPU
utilization what is single thread CPU
correct and especially what is your
memory used right memory used in the
percentage right and also you can see
um latency if you have any latency high
input latency it shows you the latencies
right and uh frame related all the frame
related like frame render time frame
render uh
right and then also so and so on so
basically you have enormous list of
metrics related to
um
blurriness blocking X right and contrast
brightness of the screens and also
cumulate to network spot packets and
monitoring and collecting info about the
CPU load I showed you the CPU load also
right and memory load battery
consumption all these metrics you can
have and all these collected metrics
right these Telemetry data processed by
mobile age
so what happens there is a mobile engine
ERS device cloud and that mobile engine
will collect all these uh Telemetry data
and which is being processed by mobile
agent and it results it gives you the
result of mobile AI engine to create
issue cards
which gives you
a overview of user experience and
performance
issues where are the issue cards these
are your issue cards if you see impact
score
created in patch code and it created one
in issue card if you see this is one
issue card unoptimized resource
and then loading animation domain
sharing right and then you have show
downloads
so these are all the issue cards it
generated by
you are
mobile AI engine slow server expand this
it gives you all the information your
application waited longer than uh 500
milliseconds to receive first byte in
HTTPS responses from those hosts right
what can I do what is the solution and
what is another issue card uh there is
another issue card slow downloads just
click here and if you see if you expand
these HTTP responses took longer than
500 milliseconds right and then
unoptimized resource a client downloaded
resources as
uncompressed plain text what can I do so
basically it generates all the issue
cards by seeing these issue cards you
can simply
take action so your developer can take
action and then he can enhances the
application and again and again again he
can deploy uh the enhanced application
into your device and you can you can
start testing again so that's how you
can slowly improve your
device or improve your application so
basically you are not only performing
your automation testing and also you are
giving a feedback of performance also
right in the terms of networks in terms
of uh frame rates in terms of image
qualities in terms of blurriness right
all these feedback can be sent to your
developer immediately your developer can
take your action okay that is
performance session section and there is
another section called performance
monitoring habitants performance
monitoring
performance monitoring
what happens performance session can be
grouped to your user flows okay how
let's go back here let me go here okay
if you see uh let's go here now I want
to create user flows let's say here add
to user flow if I add this you to user
flow once you add this to your user flow
test
Chrome now what I'm saying
Chrome
YouTube so I'm creating a new
user flow okay which forms so basically
once you create this new user flow okay
once you create new user flow once you
you did that you can monitor all the
collected
you can monitor all the collected
information so where in performance
monitoring section
okay so once you add your user flow
you can monitor collected metrics
user experience and performance kpis
over time so basically what happens
let's say you improved your application
your developer improved your application
again you deployed into a device and
again you are performing you are doing
automation testing so if there is an
improvement in your
application performance you can track
here see this is your
data set where you can
understand how user experience and
performance kpis are evolving over time
while you are making enhancements to
your mobile application
okay you understand right and also you
can compare two different sessions
against each other let's say a choose
location to compare against so this is
your
choose a device and then what is the
location that you want to compare with
so if you want to compare the axis I
mean your app how the application
behaves from us compared to India right
you can compare that also so basically
you can monitor all your kpis
improvements over the time by using
performance monitoring and by using
performance sessions you can monitor all
the metrics as I told you right and then
by using remote control you can access
your
devices
and you can mirror your devices right so
hope you all understand
these three main features remote control
performance sessions and performance
monitoring these three main sections of
your tricentis device Club okay so I
never see
these many advantages like performance
sessions and performance monitoring in
any other cloud
providers like Source Labs or browser
stack right all these providers you have
in the market but this try sentence
device cloud is providing you lot and
lot of
advantages lot and lot of features
while accessing your price on this
device load so in my next session I am
going to show you how can you connect
this Tyson is device Cloud by using
tri-center Stocker and by using testing
automation tools okay so if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries hope you all understand how this
new product called tricent is device
Cloud works and what are all the
features and advantages this try
sentence device cloud is having compared
to other Cloud providers please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank you
[Music]